Finding aid for Jesse Siddall Reeves Papers, 1853-1942
Bentley Historical Library
- Photographs
  - Various, include portraits; photographs of international law classes and meetings; and photographs of camping trips (1911-1913) in Ontario with other University of Michigan faculty members, 4 folders (Box 14)
Comments on the election of 1904 in the correspondence between Reeves and his brother Will in Oct. and Nov. of that year.
Presidents--United States--Election--1908.
Oct. 13 and 28, 1908, making extensive comments on the Taft-Bryan campaign.
Presidents--United States--Election--1912.
July 1912
Presidents--United States--Election--1920.
March 1920 on the Hoover for president movement; also comments on the election in the correspondence of Oct.-Nov. 1920.
Presidents--United States--Election--1928.
Dec. 10, 1927; comments in letters of Reeves to James Pollock commenting on Hoover, Coolidge, etc.
Presidents--United States--Election--1932.
Feb. 14, 1932 and Nov. 20, 1932.
Presidents--United States--Election--1936.
Correspondence with his brother Will in Oct. and Nov. 1936.
Presidents--United States--Election--1940.
May-Nov. 1940
Ray, P. Orman (Perley Orman), 1875.
1920-1926.
Root, Elihu, 1845-1937.
Oct. 28, 1927
Rowe, Leo S., 1871-1946.
1923-1931
Russo-Japanese War, 1904-1905.
Oct. 22, 1904, letter from A. Gerber in Germany.
Ruthven, Alexander Grant, 1882-
Apr. 1925, May 1 and Dec. 18, 1930; Jan. 12, Feb. 27, Apr. 17, 1931; Apr. 18, Nov. 30, 1932; Apr. 22, 1933, May 26 and 31, 1933
Sanders, Henry A. (Henry Arthur), 1868-1956.
Jan. 27, 1929
Sayre, Francis Bowes, 1885-1972.
Telegram, Oct. 16, 1925; letter, Oct. 19, 1925
Schmitt, Bernadotte Everly, 1886-1969.
Dec. 4, 1922, June 4, 1923, Nov. 8, 1923, Dec. 8, 1923; Oct. 4, 1924
Sforza, Carlos, conte, 1872-1952.
Oct. 8, 1932, March 1933
Shotwell, James Thomson, 1874-1965.
June 24, 1925
Smith, Shirley Wheeler, 1875-1959.
Jan. 16, 1931
Society for International Law.
ca. 1920-1942
Stone, Ralph, 1868-1956.
Apr. 10, 1928
Townsend, Charles E. (Charles Elroy), 1856-1924.
Jan. 12, 1923
University of Michigan--Buildings.
Information on projected University building needs in papers for 1927 when Reeves was a member of the Committee on University Needs
University of Michigan. School of Dentistry.
Correspondence, March 1928, with Marcus Ward, dean of the dental school, concerning dental school admission requirements.
University of Michigan. School of Education.
Letter of Feb. 16, 1916 of John Effinger on the department of education; report and recommendation on the department, Mar. 14, 1916; and report, Dec. 1920 on its future.
University of Michigan. Dept. of Germanic Languages and Literatures.
Letter, Feb. 8, 1928, of John Effinger to Reeve discussing the chairmanship of the department German and its reorganization.
University of Michigan. Engineering Research Institute.
Proposal for an engineering research institute made to the committee on special needs of the University, in letter March 18, 1929
University of Michigan. Institute of Public Administration.
Many papers of the bureau of government after its organization at Reeves' instigation in Feb. 1913, especially for the first years of its existence, also letter, Apr. 27, 1933, on development of the bureau
University of Michigan. Senate.
Papers on the plan for reorganizing the University Senate, 1930-1931
University of Michigan. University College.
Correspondence and other papers, 1928, dealing with the proposal for establishing a University College
Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.
Letters, Jan. 9, 1929, Apr. 8, 1932, Apr. 13, 1932, Feb. 1, 1934, Mar. 4, 1934, Mar. 17, 1934, and Feb. 20, 1937; also correspondence in Sept. 1936 concerning Reeves finding among his students a young assistant for Vandenberg
VanLoon, Hendrik Wilhelm, 1882-1944.
March 24, 1914, May 2, 1914, March 13, 1915, March 20, 1915, Apr. 12, 1915
VanTyne, Claude Halstead, 1869-1930.
Letters, Sept. 17, 1913 (on Van Tyne's European trip) and Mar. 18, 1924
Vollenhoven, C. V.
1925-1926
Voyages and travel--United States
A wealth of letters by Reeves, his colleagues, and friends, commenting fully on their various travels in Europe, the Philippines, South America, and providing eye-witness accounts of political development especially the letters of the 1930's on the rise of fascism and the march toward World War.
Welles, Sumner, 1892.
May 21, 1938 and Dec. 1939
White, William Allen, 1868-1944.
May 18, 1925, of William Allen White regarding the University presidency.
Wickersham, George W. (George Woodward), 1858-1936.
June 15, 1925; May 6 and 19, 1926
Wilson, George Grafton, 1863-1951.
May 25, June 3, 1925; May 5, 1926; Mar. and Apr. 1937; Nov. 21, 1938; Dec. 12, 1938
Winter, John Garrett, 1881-1956.
Mar. 1, 1937 written while Winter was traveling in France.
World War, 1914-1918--Education and the war
Excellent letters from Germans and allied scholars on the war, especially Aug. 16, 1914, Sept. 1914, Nov. 27, 1914, Jan. 9, 1915, Feb. 22, 1915, Apr. 12, 1915, May 13, 1916, Aug. 12, 1916, Nov. 1, 1916, Dec. 12, 1917, Jan. 10, 1917; also letters of Reeves on his experiences as an officer in U.S. Signal Corps, especially in letters to his brother in 1917-1918; letter, Oct. 16, 1917, of Jesse Reeves to his wife discussing firing of Eggert from the University of Michigan faculty for alleged German sympathies during World War I.
Wright, Quincy, 1890-1970.
Letters, Jan. 5, 1922, Aug. 1, 1923, June 17, 1925, Jan. 13, May 26, July 23, 1926, Apr. 3, 1929, Apr. 19, 1929, May 1, 1930, May 8 and 23, 1930, and Oct. 1931, from Quincy Wright.
Yntema, Hessel E.
Letters, 1915-1917, from Hessel Yntema who was then studying at Oxford and containing full comments on the European war.